<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-09T13:01:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">TaylorInTech</title><subtitle>Personal Blog</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Believe Bigger</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/09/20/believe-bigger.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Believe Bigger" /><published>2019-09-20T18:54:40-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T18:54:40-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/09/20/believe-bigger</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/09/20/believe-bigger.html">&lt;p&gt;Believe Bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The books I’ve been interested in lately include a lot of self reflection and forward thinking books, including “Believe Bigger” by Marshawn Evans Daniels.  I wanted to share my thoughts and important takeaways from these books as others may find it relatable as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my previous post, I talked about feeling lost and unsure how to spend my extra time not spent at work. DeVon Franklin expressed that in order to become an expert in the field you want to be in, you have to prepare and study.  Ask questions, listen, and meet people.  Maximize your potential and manage your time.  One of the things I’ve asked myself for the past few years is how can I take full advantage of the opportunities around me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I asked myself, how did I want to use my time to prepare for the next big thing in my life?  Where did I want to take my career?  What are the most important aspects for a career to be satisfying and fulfilling to you?  It is important to recognize the value of what you do, who you are, and who you aspire to be.  Everyone has a gift.  A gift is what you do the absolute best with the least amount of effort.  When I first thought about what my gift was, I thought it was helping others but I realized that might be more of a passion that I want to include into my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to CliftonStrengths, my strengths include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restorative: adept at dealing with problems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Achiever: satisfaction in being busy and productive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Positivity: contagious enthusiasm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Woo: love the challenge of meeting new people and making a connection with someone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relator: enjoy close relationships with others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminded me that I find joy by being around others and having deep connections, staying busy and upbeat, and solving problems.  Life isn’t stagnant.  We were meant to grow and continuously learn.  How can I take my strengths and use them to acheive my goals?  My first thought that I’ve been wrestling with is grad school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some colleagues recommended the Georgia Tech online program because it is convenient, doesn’t break the bank and allows me to continue to work full time in the office.  Some recommended Stanford and MIT, but studying on campus to be able to network with other classmates and get the full experience.  Others were more in favor of learning on the job and saving the money.  I love learning.  That is one thing that will never change, but there are different ways to learn other than in a classroom. I can learn from coworkers on the job, or take the initiative to do further research on my own with all the material and tools within my grasp.  All are valid options with reasonable factors to consider so I figured I would at least try and apply to the various master programs of interest and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think as people grow, goals might change or alter so it’s important to remember that you can refine your game plan.  Find a career path that will allow you to love what you do every day and grow in ways you might not have planned for.  Keep adding to your network and stay connected with the field you want to be an expert in.  Watch how trends change and overlap.  Look at set backs as set ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Hart’s “I can’t make this up: Life Lessons” talks about his dedication to be a comedian when time after time he could have given up.  Not only does he emphasize the importance of hard work and determination, but also the importance of believing in yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halfway through my first computer programming class my sophomore year of college, I took a leap of faith and changed my major.  I knew that I enjoyed problem solving and despite the program being daunting, I had to believe in myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding a way to pursue and master that gift in a way that makes a difference in the world&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Believe Bigger.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/09/04/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my blog!" /><published>2019-09-04T18:54:40-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-04T18:54:40-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/09/04/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/09/04/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;I wanted to share my experiences from college to the job hunt, to landing my first job and moving to a completely new state. Everything that I would tell my younger self about from interview prep, to networking, and other career-related topics. Especially going into a male-dominated field, I wanted to share my perspective on what it’s like working in the tech industry as a woman of color.  My hope is by sharing my story that you’ll find something that is helpful or relatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comments are welcome! I would love to hear your thoughts and any new blog topics you would like me to write about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make every day and every action intentional.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I wanted to share my experiences from college to the job hunt, to landing my first job and moving to a completely new state. Everything that I would tell my younger self about from interview prep, to networking, and other career-related topics. Especially going into a male-dominated field, I wanted to share my perspective on what it’s like working in the tech industry as a woman of color. My hope is by sharing my story that you’ll find something that is helpful or relatable.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Not All Sunshine and Rainbows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/30/not-all-sunshine-and-rainbows.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Not All Sunshine and Rainbows" /><published>2019-08-30T18:54:40-06:00</published><updated>2019-08-30T18:54:40-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/30/not-all-sunshine-and-rainbows</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/30/not-all-sunshine-and-rainbows.html">&lt;p&gt;There are definitely days where the rain, thunder, and lightning come down, figuratively and literally. But figuratively speaking, there will be days that are harder than others. I didn’t have a storm day until two months in, but it hit me hard and lasted about a week. I wasn’t sure what was bothering me, but I suddenly didn’t have any motivation to go to the gym, take a dance class, or get up and play the piano. I wasn’t in the mood to be around people which is odd for me because I get my energy from others. I think part of the honeymoon phase of moving to a new place was starting to wear off and things started to slow down. I had finally gotten my apartment all set up, I was settling into work and now I needed to figure out what to do with all this new free time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I could remember, I was always busy. There was always a schedule, structure that kept me going from one thing onto the next. Class, work, dance, music, homework, sleep, repeat. Come college, also brought more extracurricular commitments and organizations but I wouldn’t change any of it. Now that I’ve graduated, I realized I have to create my own routine again but it looks a little different. I don’t bring work home and now have the ability to pursue interests that I didn’t have time for before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will I spend my time after 5pm everyday? What are my goals for this year? 5 years from now? And even 10?  For the past 4 years all I could think about was do well in my classes, get to graduation, and find a job.  But now, what do I want out of my career? What are my milestones?  I had to spend time thinking about this because I had always had a goal in mind. I came up with three themes that I wanted to keep: continuous learning, intentional social commitment, and a consicous artistic engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuous Learning.
I never want to stop learning.  This includes learning about technology, security, the world, art, or music inside or outside a classroom.  I have considered getting my Masters in Computer Science and specializing in Machine Learning, but I’ve also considered enrolling in online 5 day courses on specialized topics.  I also learn everyday from colleagues at work, from the way they manage people or a project and conduct themselves in front of clients to discovering new strategies in product management, python libraries, etc.  Further, I hope to dive deeper into the Security world and this can be achieved by attending conferences, technical talks, and continuing my research on related topics. Technical conferences are not only great for staying up to date on the latest topics and problems in the field you are in, but also for expanding your network which leads me to my next goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intentional Social Commitment.
I believe that social engagement helps people grow at a faster rate and overcome barriers they didn’t think was possible when they aren’t doing it alone. For example, feedback is key when trying to improve on any skills or area of your life.  Feedback helps you understand where you may be lacking or show you a different perspective that you hadn’t previously considered.  With feedback, comes support and encouragement.  Those by your side want you to succeed and reach your goals and you should want the same for them.  We are stronger and better together so why not intentionally make it a priority to help each other grow?  This doesn’t mean holding someone’s hand and micromanaging their every move, but it can be small check ins here and there.  In addition, be intentional with the people you surround yourself with.  Who are you allowing to influence you?  Surrounding myself with not only like-minded people, but also people who will push you is important.  Networking with people can have such a great impact on your life if you let it.  It builds authentic connections with others and can open doors to places that weren’t on your radar/map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consicous Artistic Engagement.
Art has always been a huge part of who I am because it allows me to express myself in a way that words fail to.  I want to make a commitment to myself that I will always consicously pursue some type of art for the health of my mind, body, and soul.  Specifically, songwriting and playing piano and guitar has been on the back burner while in school, but I want to continue to develop these skills further.  Dance is a great active outlet that I can’t forget is a blessing.  There was a time when it was very probable I wouldn’t dance again and I won’t take it for granted.  Painting, sketching, and photography have always been interests but I haven’t been able to dive very deep into each of them yet.  It is something I am looking forward in doing, especially since others in my life also share those interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that by focusing on each of the intertwined themes, I will be able to watch myself and others grow and fill my time in a meaningful way.  Share your themes in the comments below, I would love to hear them!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">There are definitely days where the rain, thunder, and lightning come down, figuratively and literally. But figuratively speaking, there will be days that are harder than others. I didn’t have a storm day until two months in, but it hit me hard and lasted about a week. I wasn’t sure what was bothering me, but I suddenly didn’t have any motivation to go to the gym, take a dance class, or get up and play the piano. I wasn’t in the mood to be around people which is odd for me because I get my energy from others. I think part of the honeymoon phase of moving to a new place was starting to wear off and things started to slow down. I had finally gotten my apartment all set up, I was settling into work and now I needed to figure out what to do with all this new free time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Looking Back</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/23/looking-back.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking Back" /><published>2019-08-23T18:54:40-06:00</published><updated>2019-08-23T18:54:40-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/23/looking-back</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/23/looking-back.html"></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A New Beginning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/a-new-beginning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A New Beginning" /><published>2019-08-16T18:54:40-06:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T18:54:40-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/a-new-beginning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/a-new-beginning.html">&lt;p&gt;The reason I started this blog was to capture key experiences and lessons I’ve learned as a woman in technology, the oldest of six, and an avid artist.  I recently made a huge transition in my life and I wanted a space to be able to share my story.  So with that, we’ll start with graduation this past May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I graduated from the University of San Diego with a Bachelors in Computer Science.  My college experience was particularly impactful due to the people I surrounded myself with in and outside of the classroom.  The “Looking back” post goes deeper into what I learned at USD, tips, and how it shaped me.  The Engineering school quickly became my second home after diving head first into it all.  Walking the halls of Loma, seeing my friends every day, and staying up those long nights struggling as a class on a project is what I miss the most.  But we all have to grow up eventually and before I knew it, it was May.  Graduation time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would mean we would all go out into the world to pursue our dreams and passions, but separately.  Some of us would get a sense of true independence this time.  I wasn’t ready to say goodbye to the comfort of knowing San Diego like the back of my hand or to the second family I had developed away from home.  But I had accepted a job in Albuquerque, New Mexico, over 770 miles away and roughly 12 hours away by car.  I admit I was nervous about moving to a new state that I had never been to, except for the interview, all on my own with no family and friends nearby.  Still, the eager side of me told me to brush off the worries and jump.  So I did. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On June 19th, 2019, I drove to Albuquerque with a car packed to the brim excited to see what this new chapter held.  I signed a lease to an apartment that I had never seen in person and fortunately, it turned out to be the perfect fit.  One thing that I soon realized was that the cost of living is significantly lower than in San Diego.  Gas is half the price, around two dollars, and rent was affordable for a single recent graduate.  Albuquerque has about half a million people, about one third of San Diego’s population, leaving traffic close to nothing in New Mexico.  The landscape is beautiful and much different than I had imagined.  I am constantly mesmerized by the mountains and I always know which way home is by finding the Sandia mountains.  A hiking trail is 5 minutes from my apartment and work is less than 10 minutes away.  I had heard about the weather in Albuquerque being bipolar but I think I can say I’ve experienced it now considering I moved here right as the monsoon season began.  It usually gets into the 90s around noon and stays close to 100 degrees until sunset.  Albuquerque really does see all four seasons and sometimes all in one day!  It can be 96 degrees and start pouring with thunder and lightning for about 30 minutes then it’s back to clear skies.  That’s something I’ll have to get used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June 24th was my first day at the new job and it was more than I could have imagined it would be.  I was so excited I showed up at 7:30am, but it took me until about 7:52am to get out of the car and actually go inside.  The normal jitters you would expect but times ten.  I kept telling myself, “Taylor be cool. Don’t smile so much. BE CHILL” but I couldn’t help it.  My manager organized a team lunch and the people at the company are beyond kind and welcoming.  As a part of my orientation training, I had one on one meetings throughout the week with the VP of Operations, the Co-Founder and Head of Corporate Development, VP Governance, Chief Security Officer, and the Director from each department.  Each covered a different topic and I received personal training and access to these brilliant people who in turn, each encouraged me to reach out to them if I needed anything.  That amazes me.  As I went through my orientation and was informed of the company’s history and origin, values, departments breakdowns, and the products and services, the pieces started to fall together to paint a cohesive picture of who the company is and my role in it.  The company culture is collaborative, innovative, and inclusive.  The people really do make the company.  They are hard-working, intelligent, and lively people that I truly enjoy working with every day.  There are comments made throughout the day that make me laugh, interactions that I’ve watched between others that amaze me, and intelligent conversations I’ve heard that challenge me to work hard and inspire me to learn the most I can from others.  I am excited to shadow other pen testers and learn the most I can from co-workers in and outside of my team.  The hierarchy of the company is flat in the sense that executives make themselves available to anyone and everyone!  You don’t have to go through others or jump through hoops to speak with them if you need to.  It honestly is a family and everyone is always willing to help each other out in any way they can.  People often say find joy in your work but I was lucky enough to not only love what I do but also love the people I work with and the company I work for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that I found important to keep in mind is that it’s the little things that make a difference.  For example, addressing people by their name or remembering things about people that are shared through break room small talk.  It helps grow authentic relationships with people and has really helped me feel right at home.  Every day is unique and it’s what you make the most out of it.  Look at set backs as set ups for something better.  I’ve discovered so much about myself, the city, and the job from the little time I’ve been in Albuquerque and I’m looking forward to continuing to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The reason I started this blog was to capture key experiences and lessons I’ve learned as a woman in technology, the oldest of six, and an avid artist.  I recently made a huge transition in my life and I wanted a space to be able to share my story. So with that, we’ll start with graduation this past May.</summary></entry></feed>